const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 30-year-old man is brought into the emergency as he has overdosed on an unknown drug. On examination, his pupils are pinpoint, nonreactive to light, his breathing is sighing and pre-regular in pattern, and his body is profusely sweating. What do you think based on these findings he has overdosed on?","answers":[{"option":"Milk of magnesia","bool":false},{"option":"Naloxone","bool":false},{"option":"Naphthalene","bool":false},{"option":"Kerosene oil","bool":false},{"option":"Morphine","bool":true}]},{"id":1,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which type of fractures are seen with child abuse?","answers":[{"option":"Spalding fractures","bool":false},{"option":"Greenstick fractures","bool":false},{"option":"Nobbing fracture","bool":true},{"option":"Buckle fractures","bool":false},{"option":"Pathologic fractures","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A dead body of a girl was brought for autopsy. On examination, she was pregnant, and severe injuries were observed in her pelvic area. On inquiry, her mother told that she tried to criminally induce abortion during which she died within minutes. What is the most probable cause of death?","answers":[{"option":"Peritonitis","bool":false},{"option":"Septicemia","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary hemorrhage","bool":false},{"option":"Vagal inhibition","bool":true},{"option":"Renal Failure","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"An 11-year old boy presents with the complaint of swelling in his feet for the past 4 weeks. He is otherwise in good health and gives no previous history of any illness. Physical examination reveals pitting edema of the lower legs and a swollen abdomen. Urinalysis shows 4+ protein but no RBCs or WBCs.The treating physicians should consider which of the following conditions in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Minimal change disease","bool":true},{"option":"Pyelonephritis with acute tubular necrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Renal cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Post-streptococcal glomerulonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Wilms tumor","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following regions of nephrons is most affected in toxin-mediated acute tubular necrosis?","answers":[{"option":"Distal convoluted tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Collecting tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Ascending limb of loop of Henle","bool":false},{"option":"Descending limb of loop of Henle","bool":false},{"option":"Proximal convoluted tubule","bool":true}]},{"id":5,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"What is the role of anti-diuretic hormone in the human body?","answers":[{"option":"Helps regulate absorption of chloride","bool":false},{"option":"Helps regulate absorption of potassium","bool":false},{"option":"Helps regulate absorption of sodium","bool":false},{"option":"Helps regulate water balance in the body","bool":true},{"option":"Helps regulate absorption of phosphate","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 67-year-old male who is a known case of chronic renal failure (CRF) comes for his follow-up visit to the nephrologist. His creatinine is stable, however, his bicarbonate is 15 mEq/L. In order to prevent metabolic bone disease, his serum bicarbonate levels should be maintained at what level?","answers":[{"option":"<40 others","bool":false},{"option":"> 25 mEq","bool":false},{"option":"> 21 mEq","bool":true},{"option":"< 21 mEq","bool":false},{"option":"< 10 mEq","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 30-year-old unmarried woman came to a doctor and requested her to induce an abortion. The doctor refused and told the women there is severe punishment for criminal abortion in Pakistan. What is the punishment of criminal abortion before babies' organs are formed in Pakistan?","answers":[{"option":"3 years imprisonment if with consent","bool":true},{"option":"1/20 diyat of the child","bool":false},{"option":"7 years imprisonment","bool":false},{"option":"Full diyat of the child","bool":false},{"option":"3 years imprisonment if without consent","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 27-year-old woman presents with complaints of an increased urinary frequency with dysuria for the past 4 days. A urinalysis reveals sp. gr. 1.014, pH 7.5, no glucose, no protein, no blood, nitrite positive, and many WBC's. She has a serum creatinine of 0.9 mg/dL. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Cystitis","bool":true},{"option":"Urinary lithiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Lupus nephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Malakoplakia","bool":false},{"option":"Urothelial carcinoma","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A fetus wrapped in an old newspaper was found in the garbage, brought by police to the medico-legal section for age determination. Haase's rule states what?","answers":[{"option":"Crown Rump length of the fetus in cms gives age in months in 1st five month","bool":false},{"option":"Square root of crown rump length in cm gives age of fetus in 1st five months","bool":false},{"option":"Crown rump length of fetus in inches gives age in months in 1st five months","bool":false},{"option":"Square root of crown-heel length in cm gives age of fetus in 1st five months","bool":true},{"option":"Crown heel length of the fetus in inches gives age in months in 1st five months","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A child of 5 years was brought to ED, with multiple bruises of different ages the child is a case of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Sudden infant death syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Culpable homicide not amounting to murder","bool":false},{"option":"Accidental injuries","bool":false},{"option":"Battered baby syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Act of omission by parents","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"Filicide is defined by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Killing of a new born child by the parents","bool":true},{"option":"Synonymous with criminal abortion","bool":false},{"option":"Killing of an illegitimate child","bool":false},{"option":"Killing of a disabled new born child","bool":false},{"option":"Killing of viable fetus inside the uterus","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 30-year-old male presented, to the outpatient department with a high-grade fever and sore throat for the last 3 days. For one day he noticed blood in urine and facial puffiness. On examination, his blood pressure was 150/90mmHg with mild pedal and facial edema. What are the likely diagnoses?","answers":[{"option":"Nephrotic syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Lupus nephritis","bool":false},{"option":"IgA nephropathy","bool":true},{"option":"Post-streptococcal glomerulonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Wegener's granulomatosis","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 6-month-old boy presented in emergency for high-grade fever. His blood CP results showed a high WBC count and CRP (C-reactive protein). Blood culture and urine culture confirmed the presence of E. coli. The physician came to the conclusion that the baby is suffering from a urinary tract infection that might be due to a congenital anomaly. Which one of the following is true related to congenital defects?","answers":[{"option":"Vesico-ureteral reflux","bool":true},{"option":"Crossed fused renal ectopia","bool":false},{"option":"Horse shoe kidney","bool":false},{"option":"Renal dysplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Multicystic dysplastic kidney","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 55-year-old man presents with generalized edema and ascites. Laboratory tests show: a total serum protein of 5.2g/dl (range: 5.5-8.0g/dl), albumin of 1.9g/dl (range: 3.5-5.5g/dl), and serum cholesterol of 540mg/dl. 24-hour urine collection reveals 4.8gms of protein loss. Urine contains many hyaline casts but no RBCs or WBCs. Immuno-fluorescence on renal biopsy shows granular sub-epithelial deposits along the glomerular basement membranes. Which one of the following would be the most appropriate glomerular pathology involved?","answers":[{"option":"Minimal change disease","bool":false},{"option":"Membranous nephropathy","bool":true},{"option":"Focal segmental glomerulosclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Goodpasteurs syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Membranoproliferative glomerulonephritis","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"Before a transplant, the renal transplant team visits the patient to take consent about the procedure and also from the family after counseling. For valid consent, the patient should be which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Social","bool":false},{"option":"Mature","bool":true},{"option":"Autonomous","bool":false},{"option":"Competent","bool":false},{"option":"Confident","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 20-year-old man is brought into the emergency room after a morphine overdose.  Upon examination, he is unconscious, pupils are pinpoint and non-reactive. Several injection marks are seen on his arms. What is the immediate treatment after maintaining the airway, breathing, and circulation?","answers":[{"option":"Naloxone with pethidine","bool":false},{"option":"Naloxone with gastric lavage","bool":false},{"option":"Gastric lavage","bool":false},{"option":"Naloxone","bool":true},{"option":"Gastric lavage with tannic acid","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"In Pakistan, on which grounds is abortion justifiable?","answers":[{"option":"Humanitarian grounds","bool":false},{"option":"Social grounds","bool":false},{"option":"Eugenic grounds","bool":false},{"option":"Therapeutic grounds","bool":true},{"option":"Threatened","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"During the first three months, what is the best-skilled method of termination of pregnancy?","answers":[{"option":"Electricity","bool":false},{"option":"Vaccum aspiration","bool":true},{"option":"Abortion stick","bool":false},{"option":"Prostaglandins","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 22-year-old woman presents with swelling of the legs. On urinalysis, there was increased proteinuria. She is diagnosed to have tubulointerstitial nephritis. It could have been drug-induced. It is characterized by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Increased urinary sugar level","bool":false},{"option":"Appearance of symptoms after about two weeks of exposure","bool":true},{"option":"Decreased blood urea nitrogen","bool":false},{"option":"Dose dependent severity of the disease","bool":false},{"option":"Increased glomerular filtration rate and oliguria","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A graduate student is planning to make a high-altitude climb in South America while on vacation. He will not have time to acclimate slowly to the altitude. What drug is useful in preventing high-altitude sickness?","answers":[{"option":"Amiloride","bool":false},{"option":"Desmopressin","bool":false},{"option":"Ethacrynic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Demeclocycline","bool":false},{"option":"Acetazolamide","bool":true}]},{"id":21,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 9-year-old boy is brought to the clinic with complaints of cola-colored urine. He has a past history of being treated for a sore throat infection 3 weeks ago. His blood pressure is 145/95 mmHg. Urinalysis reveals red cell casts. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Post-streptococcal glomerulonephritis","bool":true},{"option":"IgA nephropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Goodpasture's syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Alport syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Membranous glomerulopathy","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"One of the signs of remote delivery in the living women is the presence of linea nigra a dark line of pigmentation in what location?","answers":[{"option":"From umbilicus to ensiform cartilage","bool":false},{"option":"From pubis to ensiform cartilage","bool":true},{"option":"Around umbilicus","bool":false},{"option":"From pubis to umbilicus","bool":false},{"option":"Upper part of thigh","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A post mortem examination was conducted on a 38-year-old parous woman to see the signs of remote delivery, what are the findings that would confirm the diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"The external os is vertical irregular and admit 2 fingers","bool":false},{"option":"The internal os is soft, patulous, rounded with a dimple in the center","bool":false},{"option":"The top of fundus is at a lower level than that of broad ligament","bool":false},{"option":"The walls of a uterus are concave from inside forming a wider and rounded cavity","bool":true},{"option":"The cervix and body of uterus are about the same length","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"Two infants in different stages of development may be born in which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Superfecundation","bool":false},{"option":"Superfoetation","bool":true},{"option":"Heterozygotic twins","bool":false},{"option":"Ectopic pregnancy","bool":false},{"option":"Homologous artificial insemination","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A patient presented with the complaint of recurrent stones despite drinking adequate water. Which of the following is the most common renal stone?","answers":[{"option":"Magnesium ammonium phosphate","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium phosphate","bool":false},{"option":"Uric acid","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium oxalate","bool":true},{"option":"Cysteine","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following is the appropriate drug of choice for a patient having renal calcium calculi?","answers":[{"option":"Verapamil","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrochlorothiazide","bool":true},{"option":"Spironolactone","bool":false},{"option":"Amoxicillin","bool":false},{"option":"Carbapenem","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"Calculate the net filtration pressure if the value of capillary pressure is 60 mm H2O, glomerular oncotic pressure is 32 mm H2O, and bowman hydrostatic pressure is 18 mm H2O.","answers":[{"option":"15 mm H2O","bool":false},{"option":"10 mm H2O","bool":true},{"option":"0 mm H2O","bool":false},{"option":"5 mm H2O","bool":false},{"option":"20 mm H2O","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"Spalding sign is a characteristic finding of which of the following condition?","answers":[{"option":"Unborn baby in the uterus","bool":false},{"option":"Sodomy","bool":false},{"option":"Intrauterine dead fetus","bool":true},{"option":"Abortion","bool":false},{"option":"Maceration","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following is the characteristic difference between a false virgin and a true virgin?","answers":[{"option":"Wide vaginal wall","bool":false},{"option":"Funnel shaped vagina","bool":false},{"option":"Non rugosity of vaginal wall","bool":false},{"option":"Hymen edges undulated plus 2 fingers inserted","bool":true},{"option":"Narrow vagina","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which type of statistical test is commonly used if the sample size is below 30, to determine whether the mean of a population significantly differs from a specific value or from the mean of another population and to determine whether the difference is statistically significant?","answers":[{"option":"Anova","bool":false},{"option":"Logistic regression","bool":false},{"option":"Linear regression","bool":false},{"option":"T test","bool":true},{"option":"Chi square","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 10-year-old male is brought to the clinic by his parents with complaints of periorbital puffiness and pedal edema. His urine analysis shows proteinuria, absence of RBCs and casts. You suspect minimal change disease. What would the renal biopsy findings in this patient be?","answers":[{"option":"Dense deposits on subepithelial surface of basement membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Normal light microscopy and immunofluorescence","bool":true},{"option":"Sclerosis of segments of some glomeruli","bool":false},{"option":"Increased IgA deposition in mesangium","bool":false},{"option":"Crescent formation","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"An 85-year-old male is diagnosed with renal cell carcinoma. Regarding this, all of the following statements are true except?","answers":[{"option":"It is more common in men","bool":false},{"option":"In 25 percent of cases, there are no local symptoms","bool":false},{"option":"Following radical nephrectomy, radiotherapy should be given","bool":true},{"option":"Ultrasound and tri-phasic CT urography are imaging methods of choice","bool":false},{"option":"A left sided varicocele may be a presenting feature in males","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 45-year-old lady is booked for a cholecystectomy. During her preoperative workup, radiological investigations reveal multiple cystic dilations of the collecting ducts in the renal medulla. No cortical scarring is present and renal function is normal. What is the most likely cause of these findings?","answers":[{"option":"Medullary sponge kidney","bool":true},{"option":"Tubulo-interstitial nephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Childhood polycystic kidney disease","bool":false},{"option":"Adult polycystic kidney disease","bool":false},{"option":"Nephronophthisis","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 6-year-old child undergoes surgical exploration and nephrectomy for a suspected kidney tumor. His ultrasound shows an enlarged multicystic, irregular left kidney. Biopsy shows no tumor. However, there are islands of undifferentiated mesenchyme and cartilage. Which of the following is correct regarding this disease?","answers":[{"option":"Inherited disorder","bool":false},{"option":"Excellent prognosis after nephrectomy","bool":true},{"option":"Commonest genetic cause of end stage renal disease in children","bool":false},{"option":"Primary ciliopathy implicated","bool":false},{"option":"It is rarely associated with other lower urinary tract anomalies","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following is least likely to be filtered from glomerular capillaries?","answers":[{"option":"Albumin","bool":true},{"option":"Potassium","bool":false},{"option":"Inulin","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"Rapid correction of hyponatremia may cause which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Heart attack","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral edema","bool":false},{"option":"Brain herniation","bool":false},{"option":"Central pontine myelinolysis","bool":true},{"option":"Stroke","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following is the most common organism responsible for causing nephritic syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"Beta hemolytic streptococci","bool":true},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"E. coli","bool":false},{"option":"Klebsiella","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"Sexual enjoyment from inflicting pain on others as well as on oneself is called which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Sadism","bool":false},{"option":"Satyriasis","bool":false},{"option":"Masochism","bool":false},{"option":"Beastiality","bool":false},{"option":"Algolagnia","bool":true}]},{"id":39,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"According to World Health Organization (WHO), drug dependence is defined as which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Intoxication with harmful effects on society","bool":false},{"option":"Intoxication with harmful effects on himself","bool":false},{"option":"No withdrawal symptoms","bool":false},{"option":"Desire to take drug repeatedly and increase the doses","bool":true},{"option":"Chronic and periodic intoxication with harmful effects on himself and society","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following is least likely to be seen in nephrotic syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Hematuria","bool":true},{"option":"Heavy proteinuria","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased plasma colloid osmotic pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Selective proteinuria","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoalbuminemia","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A patient presents to the emergency room with complaints of diarrhea and vomiting for one day. He is semi-conscious and severely dehydrated. What is the first-line management in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Oral fluid replacement","bool":false},{"option":"Oral antibiotics","bool":false},{"option":"IV antibiotics","bool":false},{"option":"KYB diet","bool":false},{"option":"IV fluid replacement","bool":true}]},{"id":42,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 55-year-old male with COPD presents to the clinic with increased severity of shortness of breath. His immediate arterial blood gases show respiratory acidosis. What is the first step in the interpretation of arterial blood gases?","answers":[{"option":"Anion gap","bool":false},{"option":"pH of blood","bool":true},{"option":"HCO₃ level","bool":false},{"option":"PaCO₂","bool":false},{"option":"Delta-delta gap","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A group of students was analyzing their research data set. The data showed that the frequency distribution of age of the study participants had a long tail on the right-hand side of the curve than on the left side. Compared to the median value, where does the mean value lie on the frequency distribution?","answers":[{"option":"In the center","bool":false},{"option":"Equal","bool":false},{"option":"Higher","bool":true},{"option":"Smaller","bool":false},{"option":"On the left side","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A researcher wants to find the difference between the mean hemoglobin levels of two patient groups. The groups to compare are smokers and non-smokers. What would be the test of significance that can be applied to compare these groups?","answers":[{"option":"Chi-square test","bool":false},{"option":"Fisher exact test","bool":false},{"option":"Independent sample student t-test","bool":true},{"option":"One sample student t-test","bool":false},{"option":"Paired students t-test","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A professor while analyzing the data of one thousand covid-19 hospitalized patients noted that the average C-reactive protein values of patients before and during the illness were 26.2 mg/L and 46.5 mg/L, respectively. To assess if there is a significant difference between the recorded C-reactive protein values, which of the following tests will be applied?","answers":[{"option":"Independent sample student t-test","bool":false},{"option":"Chi-square test","bool":false},{"option":"Correlation analysis","bool":false},{"option":"Paired students t-test","bool":true},{"option":"One sample student t-test","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"While conducting a data analysis you come across an extreme value in your data set. Which one of the following measures of central tendency/variance is suitable to summarize data and is least affected by extreme values in the data set?","answers":[{"option":"Mode","bool":true},{"option":"Mean","bool":false},{"option":"Arithmetic mean","bool":false},{"option":"Median","bool":false},{"option":"Range","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 10-year-old boy presents with features of nephritic syndrome following infection with streptococcal pharyngitis. Physical examination reveals facial edema. His blood pressure is 180/110 mmHg. A 24-hour urine collection test demonstrates oliguria and urinalysis shows hematuria. What finding in his urinalysis would suggest that the hematuria is caused by kidney involvement and not by bleeding from the urinary bladder?","answers":[{"option":"Hemoglobin crystals","bool":false},{"option":"Blood clots","bool":false},{"option":"Red blood cells casts","bool":true},{"option":"White blood cells casts","bool":false},{"option":"Phagocytosed hemoglobin","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"An 8-year-old boy becomes increasingly lethargic. On physical examination, he has swelling in his legs and ankles. Urinalysis shows 4+ proteinuria and no blood or glucose. 24-hour urine protein loss is 3.8 g. Immunofluorescence microscopy of renal biopsy is unremarkable. The child's condition improves after a course of corticosteroid therapy. Which of the following morphologic alteration is most likely to be responsible for his condition?","answers":[{"option":"Epimembranous IgG deposits","bool":false},{"option":"Subepithelial and subendothelial IgG deposits","bool":false},{"option":"Mesangial immune-complex deposits","bool":false},{"option":"Thickening of capillary basement membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Effacement of podocyte foot processes","bool":true}]},{"id":49,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following is most commonly associated with HIV infection?","answers":[{"option":"Membranous glomerulonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Lupus nephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Membranoproliferative glomerulonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Focal segmental glomerulonephritis","bool":true},{"option":"Minimal change disease","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"Post-streptococcal glomerulonephritis is an immunologically mediated disease. Which of the following is the classic diagnostic microscopic picture of this disease?","answers":[{"option":"Enlarged and hypercellular glomeruli","bool":true},{"option":"Hypercellular glomeruli","bool":false},{"option":"Leukocyte infiltration in glomeruli","bool":false},{"option":"Crescent formation in glomeruli","bool":false},{"option":"Enlarged glomeruli","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following glomerular disorders is a cause of nephritic syndrome in adults?","answers":[{"option":"Lipoid nephrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Focal segmental glomerulosclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"IgA nephropathy","bool":true},{"option":"Membranous glomerulopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Crescenteric glomerulonephritis","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following conditions is the most important cause of hydronephrosis?","answers":[{"option":"Urinary tract infections","bool":false},{"option":"Renal tumors","bool":false},{"option":"Congenital anomalies of the kidney","bool":false},{"option":"Obstruction to outflow of urine","bool":true},{"option":"Tuberculosis","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"Linear deposition of IgG on the basement membrane is seen in which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Nephrotic syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"IgA nephropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Shunt nephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic renal failure","bool":false},{"option":"Goodpasture syndrome","bool":true}]},{"id":54,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A patient presents with hemoptysis, renal failure, and anti-basement membrane antibodies. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Systemic lupus erythematosus","bool":false},{"option":"Churg-Strauss syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Henoch-Schönlein purpura","bool":false},{"option":"Goodpasture syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Wegener granulomatosis","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which renal calculi are common in diseases having rapid cell turnover?","answers":[{"option":"Oxalate stones","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium oxalate stones","bool":false},{"option":"Magnesium ammonium phosphate stones","bool":false},{"option":"Uric acid stones","bool":true},{"option":"Cystine stones","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"Patients with diabetes mellitus have urine with which of the following characteristics?","answers":[{"option":"Same volume and same specific gravity","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased volume and decreased specific gravity","bool":false},{"option":"Increased volume and decreased specific gravity","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased volume and increased specific gravity","bool":false},{"option":"Increased volume and increased specific gravity","bool":true}]},{"id":57,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 17-year-old girl decided to go on a starvation diet. After 1 week of starving herself, which of the following substances would most likely be found in her urine?","answers":[{"option":"Blood","bool":false},{"option":"Lipids","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose","bool":false},{"option":"Protein","bool":false},{"option":"Ketones","bool":true}]},{"id":58,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"In a patient with severe dehydration, which of the following organs most commonly becomes non-functional almost immediately?","answers":[{"option":"Lungs","bool":false},{"option":"Liver","bool":false},{"option":"Eyes","bool":false},{"option":"Kidneys","bool":true},{"option":"Pancreas","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 15-year-old girl with no known prior comorbidities presented to the emergency department with abdominal pain, vomiting, and shortness of breath for one day. She has mild tenderness in her epigastrium. She is dehydrated and hypotensive. Her blood sugar level is 450 mg/dL. What is the most common cause of a high anion gap metabolic acidosis?","answers":[{"option":"Diabetic ketoacidosis","bool":true},{"option":"Salicylate poisoning","bool":false},{"option":"Methanol poisoning","bool":false},{"option":"Ethanol poisoning","bool":false},{"option":"Renal tubular acidosis","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following functions is the kidney not responsible for?","answers":[{"option":"Cortisol production","bool":true},{"option":"Removing waste products from blood","bool":false},{"option":"Secreting renin","bool":false},{"option":"Regulation of blood pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Activating vitamin D","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"What may patients with renal failure present with?","answers":[{"option":"Electrolyte disturbance","bool":false},{"option":"Nausea and vomiting","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased urine output","bool":false},{"option":"All of these","bool":true},{"option":"Shortness of breath","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 17-year-old boy came presents to the clinic with recurrent hematuria for the past 3 months. He also states that he feels febrile and has a mild body ache. On examination, there is no anemia, edema, congested throat, or organomegaly. There is no similar personal or family history of a similar illness and no other chronic illnesses. Initial investigations reveal normal hemoglobin, albumin, urea, creatinine, and alanine aminotransferase. A urine drug report shows grade-1 parenchymal changes. During an autoimmune workup, the presence of anti-nuclear antibodies was positive, and 2+ fine speckled with normal anti-ds-DNA and complement levels. What should be the next appropriate investigation to establish a diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Urinary calcium","bool":false},{"option":"CT-pyelogram","bool":false},{"option":"Antineutrophil cytoplasmic antibodies (ANCA)","bool":false},{"option":"Kidney biopsy","bool":true},{"option":"Urine culture and sensitivity","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 4-year-old boy of weight 15 kg who is a known case of steroid dependent nephrotic syndrome presents to you with complaints of fever and flu like symptoms for the past 3 days. The child is currently in remission and receiving alternate day prednisone. What is the most appropriate management for this child's current problem?","answers":[{"option":"Treat infection, continue prednisone and add steroid sparing agents","bool":false},{"option":"Treat infection and continue alternate day prednisone","bool":false},{"option":"Treat infection and restart prednisone in full daily divided doses","bool":false},{"option":"Treat infection and shift prednisone same dose to daily dosage instead of alternate days for 2 weeks","bool":true},{"option":"Home remedies for flu and restart full dose prednisone on alternate days","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 3-year-old boy was diagnosed to have nephrotic syndrome roughly 6 months back. He went into complete remission within one week of starting oral prednisone therapy but relapsed soon afterward during therapy. He later relapsed again a few days back. What will be the most appropriate categorization of his disease?","answers":[{"option":"Infrequently relapsing nephrotic syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Steroid sensitive nephrotic syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Steroid dependent nephrotic syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Steroid resistant nephrotic syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Frequently relapsing nephrotic syndrome","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 60-year-old patient has a clinical history of frequent episodes of renal colic with calcium-containing stones. His clinical workup indicates that he has a defect in proximal tubular calcium reabsorption. Which of the following diuretic agent is most useful in the treatment of recurrent calcium stones?","answers":[{"option":"Mannitol","bool":false},{"option":"Chlorthalidone","bool":true},{"option":"Spironolactone","bool":false},{"option":"Ethacrynic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Diazoxide","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A male patient was diagnosed with liver cirrhosis. The hepatologist prescribed loop diuretics to treat his ascites. Which of the following is an important pharmacological effect of chronic therapy with loop diuretics?","answers":[{"option":"Increase in pulmonary vascular pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Teratogenic effect in pregnancy","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic alkalosis","bool":true},{"option":"Decreased urinary excretion of calcium","bool":false},{"option":"Increase in blood pressure","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 45-year-old male patient was brought to an emergency medical room with a history of a road traffic accident. Both a clinical examination and a CT scan confirmed the presence of a head injury with cerebral edema. Which of the following diuretics would be most useful for his condition?","answers":[{"option":"Acetazolamide","bool":false},{"option":"Furosemide","bool":false},{"option":"Mannitol","bool":true},{"option":"Spironolactone","bool":false},{"option":"Chlorthalidone","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following is not an established side-effect of loop diuretics?","answers":[{"option":"Hypovolemia","bool":false},{"option":"Ototoxicity","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperglycemia","bool":true},{"option":"Hyponatremia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypokalemia","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"\"Rape\" is a natural sexual offense. What section is it charged under?","answers":[{"option":"377 PPC","bool":false},{"option":"375 PPC","bool":false},{"option":"420 PPC","bool":false},{"option":"376 PPC","bool":true},{"option":"497 PPC","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"What is sexual intercourse by a man with a woman who is related to him by a blood relation termed as?","answers":[{"option":"Adultery","bool":false},{"option":"Zina","bool":false},{"option":"Rape","bool":false},{"option":"Fornication","bool":false},{"option":"Incest","bool":true}]},{"id":71,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 19-year-old unmarried female with a history of alleged kidnapping and rape was brought to the medicolegal office for examination. On genital examination, vulval bruising and torn fourchette hymen were seen. Ideally, what is the most common site of rupture of the hymen?","answers":[{"option":"3 and 9 o'clock","bool":false},{"option":"5 and 7 o'clock","bool":true},{"option":"11 and 2 o'clock","bool":false},{"option":"6 and 12 o'clock","bool":false},{"option":"4 and 7 o'clock","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"What is the probable sign of pregnancy corresponding to around 6-8 weeks, where the lower uterine segment becomes soft and compressible known as?","answers":[{"option":"Jacquemier's sign","bool":false},{"option":"Hegar's sign","bool":true},{"option":"Goodell's sign","bool":false},{"option":"Ballottement sign","bool":false},{"option":"Osiander's sign","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"What is the most reliable and only sign of recent delivery in the living?","answers":[{"option":"External os is transverse, irregular and fissured","bool":false},{"option":"Lochia serosa","bool":false},{"option":"Disappearance of Arbor vitae","bool":false},{"option":"Fundus lying 2.5 cm below umbilicus","bool":true},{"option":"Body of the uterus twice the length of cervix","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"What are the grounds under which an abortion is carried out where there is a substantial risk if the baby is born, it will likely suffer from physical and mental abnormality?","answers":[{"option":"Eugenic","bool":true},{"option":"Humanitarian","bool":false},{"option":"Environmental","bool":false},{"option":"Therapeutic","bool":false},{"option":"Socail","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"What is the Glaister-keen rod used for?","answers":[{"option":"Inserted in vagina for masturbation","bool":false},{"option":"To see defensibility of vagina","bool":false},{"option":"To determine hymen rupturing","bool":true},{"option":"To see the presence or absence of vaginal discharge","bool":false},{"option":"To induce abortion","bool":false}]},{"id":76,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A case of alleged rape has been brought to you. On examining the female victim, you determined that the hymen was fimbriated and not ruptured. Therefore, you concluded that the allegations were false. How do you differentiate between a fimbriated and a ruptured hymen?","answers":[{"option":"Ruptured hymen can occur naturally","bool":false},{"option":"Shape of notches is assymetrical in a fimbriated hymen","bool":false},{"option":"Shape of notches is bilaterally symetrical in a ruptured hymen","bool":false},{"option":"Ruptured hymen","bool":false},{"option":"Mucous membrane is intact over notches in a fimbriated hymen","bool":true}]},{"id":77,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"You examine a 40-year-old multiparous female and find hymen remnants in the form of marginal attachments that are thick and irregular. What are these attachments known as?","answers":[{"option":"Carunculae hymenales","bool":false},{"option":"Triangular projections","bool":false},{"option":"Fimbriated hymen","bool":false},{"option":"Ruptured hymen","bool":false},{"option":"Carunculae myrtiformes","bool":true}]},{"id":78,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"In the case of sodomy, who is the passive agent?","answers":[{"option":"Rapist","bool":false},{"option":"Witness of the act","bool":false},{"option":"Performer of the act","bool":false},{"option":"Hearsayer of the act","bool":false},{"option":"On whom it is performed","bool":true}]},{"id":79,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"You are asked to examine a habitual sodomite. Which of the following findings are you most likely going to find in such a case?","answers":[{"option":"Confusion","bool":false},{"option":"Bruising","bool":false},{"option":"Anal tear","bool":false},{"option":"Bleeding","bool":false},{"option":"Anal fissures","bool":true}]},{"id":80,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 22-year-old female presented with a complaint of blood in her urine. What is the initial investigation recommended for this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Urine culture","bool":false},{"option":"Urine analysis","bool":false},{"option":"CT urography","bool":false},{"option":"Ultrasound kidney, ureters, bladder","bool":true},{"option":"Urine dipstick test","bool":false}]},{"id":81,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 55-year-old male presented with the complaint of painless hematuria, hypertension, weight loss, pyrexia, and anorexia. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Prostate cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Renal cancer","bool":true},{"option":"Lower urinary tract infection","bool":false},{"option":"Urothelial bladder cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Adenocarcinoma bladder","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 45-year-old female presented with intermittent flank pain and hematuria. She was recently admitted to a hospital for acute pancreatitis. What is the likely cause of her current condition?","answers":[{"option":"Pyelonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Renal cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Lower urinary tract infection","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperthyroidism","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperparathyroidism","bool":true}]},{"id":83,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 60-year-old female came with a history of hematuria, dysuria, and troublesome lower urinary tract symptoms. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Lower urinary tract infection","bool":true},{"option":"Renal cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Adenocarcinoma bladder","bool":false},{"option":"Urothelial bladder cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Bladder stones","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 22-year-old patient with a history of recent travel to Africa is now complaining of fever, abdominal pain, and blood in the urine. What is the most likely cause?","answers":[{"option":"Pseudomonas","bool":false},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false},{"option":"Schistosoma hematobium","bool":true},{"option":"Plasmodium vivax","bool":false},{"option":"Aedes aegypti","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"An 85-year-old male presented with renal cell carcinoma. Which of the following is incorrect?","answers":[{"option":"Following radical nephrectomy, radiotherapy should be given","bool":true},{"option":"It occurs more commonly in men","bool":false},{"option":"In 25% of patients there are no local symptoms","bool":false},{"option":"A left sided varicocele may be a presenting feature in a male","bool":false},{"option":"Ultrasound and triphasic CT urography are the imaging methods of choice","bool":false}]},{"id":86,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 70-year-old man who has a history of smoking and complains of hematuria associated with pain in his left groin passes clots that are \"worm-like\". On examination, he has an enlarged left kidney and scrotal swelling. What is the investigation of choice?","answers":[{"option":"CT kidney, ureters, bladder (KUB)","bool":false},{"option":"Triphasic CT urography","bool":true},{"option":"Ultrasound abdomen","bool":false},{"option":"Ultrasound scrotum","bool":false},{"option":"Urine detailed report (DR) and culture and sensitivity (CS)","bool":false}]},{"id":87,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"Immediately after delivery, the uterine fundus lies at which of the following levels?","answers":[{"option":"12 cm above symphysis pubis","bool":true},{"option":"Can not be palpated abdominally","bool":false},{"option":"At symphysis pubis","bool":false},{"option":"At umbilicus","bool":false},{"option":"5 cm below umbilicus","bool":false}]},{"id":88,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following factors help distinguish that hematuria is of renal origin and not from the bladder?","answers":[{"option":"Gross hematuria","bool":false},{"option":"Sterile pyuria","bool":false},{"option":"WBC casts","bool":false},{"option":"RBC casts","bool":true},{"option":"Hemoglobinuria","bool":false}]},{"id":89,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following is the best treatment for euvolemic hyponatremia?","answers":[{"option":"Dextrose saline","bool":false},{"option":"Water restriction","bool":false},{"option":"0.9% saline","bool":false},{"option":"3% hypertonic saline","bool":true},{"option":"Dextrose water","bool":false}]},{"id":90,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 50-year-old female patient comes to the outpatient department with frothy urine, edema, and low urine output. She has been a known case of diabetes and hypertension for almost 20 years. Her laboratory reports show increased creatinine levels and is diagnosed with diabetic nephropathy. What is the histological appearance of diabetic nephropathy?","answers":[{"option":"Glomerulosclerosis","bool":true},{"option":"Spike and dome appearance","bool":false},{"option":"Sub-epithelial dense deposits","bool":false},{"option":"Tram tract or double contouring","bool":false},{"option":"Crescent glomerulonephritis","bool":false}]},{"id":91,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A person taking a diuretic for a heart issue is prescribed gentamicin. He later complained of dizziness and tinnitus. Which of the following drugs is responsible for these symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Acetazolamide","bool":false},{"option":"Mannitol","bool":false},{"option":"Ethacrynic acid","bool":true},{"option":"Spironolactone","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrocholorothiazide","bool":false}]},{"id":92,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"Many diuretics are known to cause hypokalemia. Which one of the following drugs causes hyperkalemia?","answers":[{"option":"Hydrochlorothiazide","bool":false},{"option":"Furosemide","bool":false},{"option":"Torsemide","bool":false},{"option":"Bumetanide","bool":false},{"option":"Spironolactone","bool":true}]},{"id":93,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 70-year-old man is planning to undergo transurethral resection of his prostate. Which of the following complications can arise after the surgery?","answers":[{"option":"Retrograde ejaculation","bool":true},{"option":"Surgery failure","bool":false},{"option":"Post operational urinary retention","bool":false},{"option":"Renal Failure","bool":false},{"option":"Dizziness","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 50-year-old male patient with a known case of diabetes presented to the outpatient department. His laboratory investigations showed hypocalcemia, hyperphosphatemia, and hyperkalemia. Which of the following can be the cause of these metabolic abnormalities?","answers":[{"option":"Homocystinuria","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic kidney disease","bool":true},{"option":"Acute tubular injury","bool":false},{"option":"Primary hyperthyroidism","bool":false},{"option":"Phenylketonuria","bool":false}]},{"id":95,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 50-year-old male patient with a known case of diabetes presented to the outpatient department. His laboratory investigations showed hypocalcemia, hyperphosphatemia, and hyperkalemia. He was diagnosed with chronic kidney failure and now complained of shortness of breath, lack of energy, and pale skin. What could be the cause of his anemia?","answers":[{"option":"Thalassemia","bool":false},{"option":"Iron deficiency anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Erythropoietin deficiency","bool":true},{"option":"Acute renal injury","bool":false},{"option":"Anemia of chronic disease","bool":false}]},{"id":96,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which investigation will be done on a woman with a complaint of urinary incontinence?","answers":[{"option":"Ultrasound KUB","bool":false},{"option":"Ultrasound bladder with pre and post void volumes","bool":false},{"option":"Urodynamic testing","bool":true},{"option":"Micturating cystoureterogram","bool":false},{"option":"Computed tomography scan","bool":false}]},{"id":97,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A student was taking a history in a surgery ward when a patient said that he had donated his kidney two years ago. Which of the following is the most common reason for someone to donate a kidney to an unknown person?","answers":[{"option":"To get rid of one kidney","bool":false},{"option":"Financial incentive","bool":true},{"option":"It is a tradition","bool":false},{"option":"It is a ritual to rise to higher level in society","bool":false},{"option":"It is an obligation according to one's religions","bool":false}]},{"id":98,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"While operating on a man after road traffic accident, doctor found scarring on a kidney. Scarring of the kidney along with dilation in a completely asymptomatic patient can be found in which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Chronic pyelonephritis","bool":true},{"option":"Acute tubular injury","bool":false},{"option":"Acute pyelonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Hematuria","bool":false},{"option":"Kidney injury due to trauma","bool":false}]},{"id":99,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 27-year-old man who lived alone in a studio died suddenly. Upon post-mortem examination, several raised yellow abscesses on the kidney surface were seen. Which of the following diseases is associated with rapid loss of renal function over days to weeks?","answers":[{"option":"Acute interstitial nephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Nephrotic syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic pyelonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute pyelonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute tubular injury","bool":false},{"option":"Rapidly progressive glomerulonephritis","bool":true}]},{"id":100,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 23-year-old female presents to the outpatient clinic with complaints of increased frequency, urgency, and dysuria for the past 2 weeks. Her history is also significant for suprapubic discomfort and her laboratory reports show increased nitrites and leukocyte count. What is the single most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Urethral stricture","bool":false},{"option":"Pyelonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Cystitis","bool":true},{"option":"Bladder stones","bool":false},{"option":"Urethritis","bool":false}]},{"id":101,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following defects is found in autosomal dominant polycystic kidney disease on a molecular level?","answers":[{"option":"Cilia and endoplasmic reticulum","bool":false},{"option":"Cilia and centrosome","bool":true},{"option":"Cilia and mitochondria","bool":false},{"option":"Podocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Brush border defect","bool":false}]},{"id":102,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"Both adult and childhood polycystic kidney disease cause end-stage renal disease. What is correct regarding autosomal recessive cystic kidney disease?","answers":[{"option":"Mostly occur in old age","bool":false},{"option":"Mostly occur in children","bool":true},{"option":"Mostly occur in both adults and children","bool":false},{"option":"Mostly occur in adults","bool":false},{"option":"Mostly occur in intrauterine period","bool":false}]},{"id":103,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following can be used as the appropriate statistical test to study the IQ levels of 25 students (sample size is less than 30)?","answers":[{"option":"Anova","bool":false},{"option":"Regression","bool":false},{"option":"Mann-Whitney U test","bool":false},{"option":"T-test","bool":true},{"option":"Chi square","bool":false}]},{"id":104,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 70-year-old male is having urinary incontinence and nocturia. He also complains of dribbling of urine and hematuria. Which investigation should be done to rule out bladder outlet obstruction?","answers":[{"option":"Urodynamic investigations","bool":true},{"option":"Endoscopy","bool":false},{"option":"Digital rectal examination","bool":false},{"option":"Prostate specific antigen","bool":false},{"option":"Cystoscopy","bool":false}]},{"id":105,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A person who is diabetic for many years develops anemia, hypocalcemia, hyperphosphatemia, fatigue, and body aches. His previous medical history reveals that he has been diagnosed with osteoporosis along with chronic renal failure for which he has been on dialysis for the past 4 months. Which of the following correctly describes his condition?","answers":[{"option":"Secondary hyperparathyroidism","bool":false},{"option":"Primary hyperparathyroidism","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic kidney disease","bool":false},{"option":"Tertiary hyperparathyroidism","bool":false},{"option":"Renal osteodystrophy","bool":true}]},{"id":106,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A patient presented to the outpatient department with a complaint of severe pain in the loin region along with oliguria, hematuria, and burning micturition. Which of the following investigations is considered a gold standard for detecting a kidney stone?","answers":[{"option":"Cystoscopy","bool":false},{"option":"Plain X-ray","bool":false},{"option":"Pyelogram","bool":false},{"option":"MRI","bool":false},{"option":"CT-KUB","bool":true}]},{"id":107,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A patient presented to the clinic with the symptoms of the nephrotic syndrome. Upon investigation, his glomeruli were found to be thick, and hypercellular with a double contouring of the glomerular basement membrane. There were thick subendothelial electron-dense deposits clearly visible. His serum levels showed hypocomplementemia, especially low levels of C3. Which of the following is the most appropriate diagnosis in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Membranoproliferative glomerulonephritis","bool":true},{"option":"IgA nephropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Focal glomerulosclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Steroid resistant nephrotic syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Minimal change disease","bool":false}]},{"id":108,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 50-year-old male presents with flank pain and urinary symptoms. A diagnosis of solitary cysts was made. A single cyst is diagnostically important for what reason?","answers":[{"option":"Is more common in males","bool":false},{"option":"Leads to renal failure in early stage","bool":false},{"option":"Appears in early childhood","bool":false},{"option":"It has to be differentiated with the renal carcinoma","bool":true},{"option":"Is a life threatening condition","bool":false}]},{"id":109,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following is the best method for waste disposal as it produces the least amount of pollution?","answers":[{"option":"Dewatering","bool":false},{"option":"Incineration","bool":true},{"option":"Thermal treatment","bool":false},{"option":"Autoclave","bool":false},{"option":"Landfill","bool":false}]},{"id":110,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 40-year-old man comes to the clinic with a complaint of bleeding and pain during and after urination. He was treated for a urinary tract infection several times in the past. Which of the following can be the cause of this condition if the pain is radiating to the wards of the perineum?","answers":[{"option":"Bladder stone","bool":true},{"option":"Renal stone","bool":false},{"option":"Benign prostate hypertrophy","bool":false},{"option":"Ureteric stone","bool":false},{"option":"Recurrent urinary tract infections","bool":false}]},{"id":111,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 30-year-old female presents to the outpatient department with complaints of urinary incontinence, fever, and painful micturition. She also complained that she sometimes sees the pus coming out along with the urine. What will be the first investigation that can be done in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Prostate examination","bool":false},{"option":"Cystoscopy","bool":false},{"option":"Mid stream urine culture and microscopy","bool":false},{"option":"Ultrasound","bool":false},{"option":"Urinalysis and culture","bool":true}]},{"id":112,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following correctly defines Montgomery tubercles?","answers":[{"option":"Pigmentation around breast","bool":false},{"option":"Enlarged sebaceous glands around nipples","bool":true},{"option":"Pigmented raised line from pubis to umbilicus","bool":false},{"option":"Pigmented lines on the chest","bool":false},{"option":"Fluid discharge from breast","bool":false}]},{"id":113,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following can be used as a first-line agent in the treatment of bladder carcinoma in situ?","answers":[{"option":"Cystectomy","bool":false},{"option":"Intravesical BCG","bool":true},{"option":"Trans urethral resection of bladder tumor.","bool":false},{"option":"Combined chemotherapy","bool":false},{"option":"Intravesical mitomycin C","bool":false}]},{"id":114,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following would have decreased serum levels in immune complex-mediated injury to the kidney?","answers":[{"option":"Creatinine","bool":false},{"option":"Hagman factor","bool":false},{"option":"Albumin","bool":false},{"option":"Complement proteins","bool":true},{"option":"Hemoglobin","bool":false}]},{"id":115,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 20-year-old female patient presented to the outpatient department with complaints of hematuria and edema. She had a history of sore throat around 14 days back. Upon investigation, it was found that her urine contained red blood cell casts and mild proteinuria while microscopy showed crescentic proliferation of glomerular epithelial cells and segmental glomerular necrosis. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Focal glomerulosclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetic nephropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Hemolytic uremic syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Rapidly progressive glomerulonephritis","bool":true},{"option":"Post infectious glomerulonephritis","bool":false}]},{"id":116,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 12-year-old boy presented to the outpatient department with the complaint of hematuria and proteinuria. He has a history of a skin infection that presented with blisters. Upon investigation by immunofluorescence microscopy, there were granular deposits of IgG and C3, and sometimes IgM in the mesangium along the glomerular basement membrane. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Membranoproliferative glomerulonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Focal segmental glomerulonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Lupus nephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Post streptococcal glomerulonephritis","bool":true},{"option":"Rapidly progressive glomerulonephritis","bool":false}]},{"id":117,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following is not present in oral rehydration therapy?","answers":[{"option":"Potassium chloride","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium chloride","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium carbonate","bool":true},{"option":"Glucose","bool":false},{"option":"Trisodium citrate","bool":false}]},{"id":118,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 29-year-old woman presents to the outpatient department with complaints of hematuria and frothy urine. She also gives a history of joint pain in small fingers, knees, and hip but there is no deformity upon examination in any of these joints. She sometimes feels irritated by bright lights. What is the probable diagnosis of this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Rapidly progressive golerulonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetes leading to nephropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Cryoglobinemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertension mediated nephropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Systemic lupus erythematosus","bool":true}]},{"id":119,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A 30-year-old female patient presented to the outpatient department with a complaint of hematuria. She had a history of alopecia, photosensitivity, and oral ulcers. She seemed very conscious about a butterfly-shaped rash on her cheeks. Upon investigation, she had a proteinuria > 0.5 g/24 hours. Which of the following correctly describes the cause of her renal condition?","answers":[{"option":"Focal sclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Migraine","bool":false},{"option":"Glomerulonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Systemic lupus erythmatosus","bool":true},{"option":"Amyloidosis","bool":false}]},{"id":120,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following is the correct term for the following statement \"Whoever causes a woman with child some of whose limbs or organs have been formed to miscarry, if such miscarriage is not caused in good faith for the purpose of saving the life of the woman\"?","answers":[{"option":"Ishqat-e-hamal","bool":false},{"option":"Ikrah-e-tam","bool":false},{"option":"Geyer-jaifah","bool":false},{"option":"Ishqat-e-janin","bool":true},{"option":"Shajah ammah","bool":false}]},{"id":121,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"Which of the following is an indication of acute tubular necrosis caused by toxins?","answers":[{"option":"Increased GFR and polyuria","bool":false},{"option":"Increased glucose concentration in urine","bool":false},{"option":"Increased GFR and oliguria","bool":false},{"option":"Reduced GFR and polyuria","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased GFR and oliguria","bool":true}]},{"id":122,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2022","question":"A person presents to the outpatient department with a complaint of urinary incontinence and burning micturition. After a detailed investigation, a digital rectal examination is performed on which his prostate gland is found to be stony hard. Which of the following can be the most probable diagnosis in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Prostate adenocarcinoma","bool":true},{"option":"Prostatitis","bool":false},{"option":"Calcified prostate","bool":false},{"option":"Inflamed prostate","bool":false},{"option":"Benign prostate hyperplasia","bool":false}]}]
export default arr